All right, in this video we are going to
discuss um running JavaScript for the
very first time and then we're also
going to discuss some JavaScript
comments. All right, in order to run
JavaScript you need a special HTML tag.
This tells the web browser that we are
no longer running HTML. We are now
running JavaScript. So it needs to work
a little differently. The way we make
this tag is we type a the word script
and then hit tab or enter. And that puts
in two script tags. Anything I type
between these two script tags is
JavaScript and not HTML. So, um, up
here, um, I typed the body tag. If I
type body between script, um, and I type
body just like we would type normal
HTML, you can see it gives me an error.
It's this red squiggly line says, "Wait
a minute, that's not supposed to exist
in a script tag." So, we'll get rid of
that. So what we can type whatever we
type here is JavaScript.
Traditional for coding is with
JavaScript is you say hello world for
your first program. So let's write hello
world. Um one of the ways we can do that
is with a pop-up box that shows up on
the screen. Um in our pop-up box we're
going to say hello world. The way you
make a pop-up box in JavaScript is you
use the keyword alert. So we're going to
say alert and then we're going to put
open parenthesis.
This says, "When you want to show an
alert, I need a message of some sort."
So, for our message, we're going to say,
"Hello world." Um, and for this video,
I'm just going to tell you to put it in
double quotes. I'll explain why in the
next video, but we're going to say
double quotes. And then we're going to
say hello world.
And then we're going to save our code.
So that's command S on a Mac, uh,
control S on a Windows, or file save in
either case, and that will save your
file. I have my live server running. If
you don't, you'll come down here and
click this button. I promise I will stop
saying that in a few videos, but just
while we're getting started, wanted to
remind you that this button is where you
can access your live server. If your
live server is already running, then you
can come over here to Safari and you can
see, tada, pop-up box. Now we are really
getting into coding. So we've got a
pop-up box. It says hello world. So now
we've run our first JavaScript and with
great power comes great responsibility.
So it's important to learn how to
comment. So inside of our script tag,
we'll we'll enter down. There are three
ways to make a comment in JavaScript.
You can use the double forward slash.
You can use the forward slash asterisk
and then asterisk forward slash. And
then that will let you comment multiple
lines. So whatever I type here is a
comment and will not cause errors
because the computer as a reminder from
the last video the computer sees the
comments but doesn't run them. So this
allows the developer to leave notes for
themselves or anyone that comes after.
So this is a multi-line comment. Double
slashes is a single line comment.
And then sorry the third way of making a
comment is actually just a keyboard
shortcut. The keyboard shortcut is
command slash or control slash on a
Windows and that puts in the two slashes
for a single line comment and then you
can type something here and this is a
comment. We are good developers so we
are going to leave ourselves a note
about what we've done here. So I'm going
to say this is my first message to the
world and then hit command or control S.
That will save it. This comment is just
for us. So it doesn't change anything
about the way the website runs, but it
means that someone coming along later
will know what our code does. And that
wraps up commenting in JavaScript and
running our first JavaScript.